Personal accident insurance, in short,
provides personal protection to a person and his family in case of accidental injury, disability, and death. This
insurance covers the person's medical costs and provides
financial security to his family in critical times. Today, in
India,
one person dies in a road accident every four minutes,
hence it has become necessary for people to
take this insurance, which
protects people from accidental death, temporary total disability, and permanent total disability. Along with this, personal
accident insurance also provides
transportation benefit, hospital cash benefit, education benefit,
curative bonus,
family discount, and worldwide coverage.
Let us now directly know about the
seven best personal accident
insurance plans. The first plan
is HDFC Ergo Personal Accident
Insurance Policy. The sum assured of this plan is
122 years. The maximum sum
insured that a person can take is
15x that of the policyholder. The policy term in this plan is one
year.  The
second plan is the SBI General Individual
Person Insurance Policy. The
entries for this plan and updates are 2265 years
and separately for children. Three months
223 are Rs. This is the maximum sum insured that a
person can take. It is one crore. Here
also the policy term is of one year only. The person can
renew it every year. The third
plan is the SBI Lombard Persistent
Policy. The entry of this plan is 265 years
maximum sum insured which is available here. The
fourth plan is Max Bupa
Select Insurance Policy. The entry of this plan is
2265 years maximum sum insured and is available here. The
Rs. 2 crore policy is available here.
Yes, here a person can take a policy between one to three
years. The fifth plan is the Secure
Personal Accident Insurance Policy. The
entries in this plan are given
till 90 years of age. The maximum sum insured
is available for Rs. 50 lakh. The
policy term can run between one to three years. The
sixth plan is the Secure Personal Accident Insurance Policy.  The plan is Future Generali
Personal Accident Insurance Suraksha
Policy. The entry for this plan is
8273 years and
325 years for children. This is the maximum sum insured that can be
taken by an individual. It is 144 times his/her monthly income. The
policy term that an individual
can choose is between one and three years. The seventh
plan is Bajaj Allianz Personal Gaadi Policy. The
entry for this plan and updates is
1*65 years and
521 years for children. This is the maximum sum insured
available for an individual.
Rupees Five Lines. The policy term in this plan is
one year, which can be renewed every year. Just
like bike insurance, personal
accident insurance policy has some
inclusions and exclusions, that is, the
things that this policy covers and what
it does not cover. Let us first talk about
inclusions, that is, what this policy
generally covers: accidental death, total and
partial disability, accidental death, and member failure.
Charges and Miscellaneous
Expenses Child Education Coverage Live
Support Benefit Ambulance Charges Bonus
Broken Bones Daily Allowance in case of loss of income
Corpse Terrorism Attack Now let's talk about
food, that is, it is not covered by this policy
Natural Death Pre-existing Disability or
Injury Pregnancy and
Childbirth Salicylic Acid and Suicide Note
Influence from Allopathic Treatment and
Drugs and Intoxicants Mental
Disorders and Complaints Criminal Act
Participation and Adventurous Activities
HIV AIDS
Sexually Transmitted Diseases Involvement in
All Activities and so on There is a
thin line difference in Health Insurance in Select Insurance.
Health Insurance in Journals and Glass
covers the hospital medical expenses incurred due to it. It does
not cover Death and Disability. On the other hand,
Personal Accident Insurance provides
compensation on death or disability caused by an accident.
Here, Post
Hospitalization Expenses are not covered.
Before taking a Personal Accident Insurance, you should know the following things.  The three things that
should be kept in mind the most are Prem
Explosions and Worldwide Insurance Coverage.
Here, for more information related to Select Insurance, you
can visit our website policy.com. If
you have any questions related to this video, then do share them with us by
commenting below.
To see more such videos related to insurance, subscribe to our channel Politics today
with bell notification.